Walter Sullivan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Newspaper and Magazine Files, 1938-1995 (Box 127-169)
  - Raw copy and drafts (Box 138)
    - Korea (before Korean War, 1950-1953), circa 1950 (Box 168)
    - Korean War, 1950-1953, circa 1951 (Box 168)
    - Trail log series, circa 1956-1957 (Box 168)
    - Unidentified flying object related, 1967-1968, undated (Box 168)
    - United Nations, 1950-1952, undated, (3 folders) (Box 168)
    - "The World Studies Itself," undated (Box 168)
  - Story ideas, 1980-1991 (Box 168)
  - Story proposals, 1956, 1983-1992 (Box 168)
- Television and Radio Files, 1951-1993 (Box 169-183)
  The bulk of this series documents the development of an unproduced television program based on his book Landprints, including proposals, fund-raising efforts, grant applications, program outlines, research files, and scripts for four episodes. Other television files include broadcast scripts for Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) news programs, the National Broadcasting Company (NBC) program “Prospects of Life on Other Planets,” and the New York University series “By the Year 2000.” Contains radio scripts for WQXR, a New York Times owned radio station and materials related to radio and television interviews, panels, and promotional appearances. This series also includes scripts for the New York Times educational cassette series “Keeping Up with the Times.”
  Correspondence, proposals, writings, scripts, photographs, research files, agreements, contracts.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic
  - "Landprints" See also Digital Files, same title (Box 169)
    - Advisors, 1988-1992 (Box 169)
    - Agreement, 1988 (Box 169)
    - Carolina bays, sinkholes, karsts, 1988-1990, undated (Box 169)
    - Checkerboard and pioneer trails, 1986-1989, undated (Box 169)
    - Cities and suburbs, 1986-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 169)
    - Coastal modification, 1981-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 169, Box 170)
    - Contacts, circa 1988 (Box 170)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1993, (5 folders) (Box 170)
    - Farming, grazing, lumbering, reforestation, 1970, 1982-1990, (2 folders) (Box 170)
    - "Fire from the Sea: Evolution of the Hawaiian Islands," undated (Box 170)
    - Fund-raising (Box 171)
      - General, 1985-1992, (5 folders) (Box 171)
      - Hawaii, 1987-1988 (Box 171)
      - International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), 1986-1989 (Box 171)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), 1987-1990 (Box 171)
      - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1986-1989 (Box 171)
    - Hawaii, 1982-1989, (1 folder) (Box 171, Box 172)
    - "Himalayas in New England," 1986-1989 (Box 172)
    - Ice (Box 172)
      - Cape Cod and Boston, Mass., 1976, 1986-1989, undated (Box 172)
      - Miscellany, 1974-1991 (Box 172)
      - Photographs, maps, diagrams, 1984-1988 (Box 172)
    - Ice ages, 1960, 1972-1975, 1982-1989 (Box 172)
    - Industry, 1987-1988, undated (Box 172)
    - Karsts, 1971, 1981, undated (Box 172)
    - Mining, open pit, 1978-1987 (Box 172)
    - Miscellany, 1976-1990, undated See also Container OV 3, same title, (1 folder); (6 folders); (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 172, Box 173, Box 174, Box 175)
    - National Science Foundation application, 1988-1989 (Box 175)
    - Outlines, circa 1985-1989, (1 folder) (Box 175, Box 176)
    - Photographs, 1983, 1989, undated, (6 folders) (Box 176)
    - Plate tectonic maps, undated (Box 177)
    - Program 1: "The Melting Pot," 1987-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 177)
    - Program 2: "The Age of Ice," 1952-1955, 1978-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 177)
    - Program 3: "Arteries of America," 1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - Program 4: "Hand of Man," 1989, undated (Box 178)
    - Proposals, 1985-1992, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - Rifts (Box 178)
      - East, 1969-1970, 1980-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 178)
      - West, 1989, undated (Box 179)
    - Rivers (Box 179)
      - Atchafalaya River, 1983-1989 (Box 179)
      - General, 1967-1976, 1987-1990, undated (Box 179)
      - Meanders on Mars and the Moon, 1989 (Box 179)
      - River power, 1984-1990 (Box 179)
    - Scouting trips, 1987-1988 (Box 179)
    - Similar television shows, 1986-1987, undated (Box 179)
    - Terranes, 1983-1987 (Box 179)
    - Venture expenses and budget, 1988-1989 (Box 179)
    - Western mountains, 1982-1989 (Box 179)
    - White, Kathy, files (Box 179)
      - Barrier Islands, 1987-1989 (Box 179)
      - Cascades, 1981-1987 (Box 180)
      - Coal, 1973, 1981-1987, undated (Box 180)
      - Columbia, S.C., 1989, undated (Box 180)
      - Connecticut, 1986-1989, undated (Box 180)
      - Drumlins, 1977-1985 (Box 180)
      - Earthquakes, 1980-1990 (Box 180)
      - Fall line cities, 1973, undated (Box 180)
      - Glaciers and the ice age, 1984-1989 (Box 180)
      - Grand Canyon, undated (Box 180)
      - Greenhouse effect, 1988 (Box 180)
      - Hatcher, Robert D., 1983-1988, undated (Box 180)
      - Industrial America, 1988, undated (Box 181)
      - Landprints: On the Magnificent American Landscape book notes, circa 1984-1989 (Box 181)
      - Loess, 1972-1987, undated (Box 181)
      - Miscellany, 1972-1989, (3 folders) (Box 181)
      - Mississippi River, 1984-1988 (Box 181)
      - Morocco, 1974, undated (Box 181)
      - Pennsylvania, 1989, undated (Box 181)
      - Photographs, 1967, 1975, undated (Box 181)
      - Plate tectonics, 1980-1987 (Box 182)
      - References, circa 1986-1989, (2 folders) (Box 182)
      - Rocky Mountains, 1980-1988 (Box 182)
      - Shiprock, circa 1963-1989 (Box 182)
      - Terranes, 1980-1988 (Box 182)
      - Volcanoes, 1980-1988, undated (Box 182)
  - Miscellaneous television shows and scripts, 1962-1976, 1986-1989, undated See also Personal File, Lectures and television, (6 folders) (Box 183)
  - Radio programs, 1951, 1961-1971, 1977, undated (Box 183)
  - Radio scripts, 1962-1968, 1980-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 183)
  - Television contracts, 1965-1979 (Box 183)
  - "Walter Sullivan on Science" cassette series, 1970-1971 (Box 183)
- Alphabetical File, 1929-1995 (Box 184-214)
  This series contains research files related to many of Sullivan’s projects, focusing mostly on topics related to his books and New York Times articles. The files comprise articles, maps, and other secondary source materials, oftentimes with notations by Sullivan. A large number of files focus on Antarctica, and feature such topics as the Deep Freeze expeditions, Admiral Richard Evelyn Byrd, treaties, photographs, manuals, and tourism. The series also includes many government publications and photographs from New Zealand from the 1940s. The files on unidentified flying objects (UFOs) are extensive and contain many articles, reports, and rare publications. Other major topics include earthquakes, volcanoes, tectonics, planets, telescopes, radioactive waste, Alaska, cosmology, water, and Hawaii.
  Research, correspondence, photographs, maps, notes, manuals, articles, pamphlets, press releases, clippings, reports, surveys, journals, newsletters.
  - Adaptive optics, 1970-1978, 1987-1992 (Box 184)
  - Agriculture, 1968, 1979 (Box 184)
  - Aircrafts (Box 184)
    - Miscellany, 1966-1970, 1978, undated (Box 184)
    - Traffic control, 1975-1982 (Box 184)
  - Alaska (Box 184)
    - Landscape, 1975-1977, undated (Box 184)
    - Miscellany, 1946, 1958, 1964, 1972-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 184)
    - Notes, 1945-1946 (Box 184)
    - Overkill, 1965-1967, 1990, undated (Box 184)
    - Prudhoe Bay, 1969-1970, undated (Box 184)
  - American Museum, Hayden Planetarium, New York, N.Y., 1957 (Box 184)
  - Antarctica (Box 184)
    - Antarctic and Southern Ocean Coalition, Committee on Antarctic Policy and Science, 1992-1993 (Box 184)
    - Antarctic drift, 1991-1992, undated (Box 184)
    - Dry valleys, 1972-1981 (Box 184)
    - East Antarctic stability, 1984, 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 185)
    - Falkland Islands Dependency Survey, 1953 (Box 185)
    - Ice, 1972-1990 (Box 185)
    - Ice surges, 1974-1991 (Box 185)
    - Icebergs, 1973-1980 (Box 185)
    - Images, 1964 (Box 185)
    - International, 1958-1963, 1976-1981, 1989-1993 (Box 185)
    - Itinerary and briefing, 1974-1976 (Box 185)
    - Living marine resources, 1978-1981, undated (Box 185)
    - Manuals and handbooks, 1990-1992, undated, (1 folder) (Box 185, Box 186)
    - Marie Byrd Land project, 1959 (Box 186)
    - Marine life, 1976-1986 (Box 186)
    - Meteorites, 1978-1986 (Box 186)
    - Mineral resources, 1975-1985 (Box 186)
    - Mining, 1974, 1994 (Box 186)
    - Miscellany (Box 186)
      - 1955-1992, undated, (5 folders) (Box 186)
      - 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 187)
    - Notes and interviews, undated (Box 187)
    - Operation Deep Freeze II, 1956-1957, undated, (3 folders) (Box 187)
    - Penguins, 1954-1958, 1978, 1991-1993 (Box 187)
    - Photographs (Box 187)
      - 1935, 1946-1956, undated, (3 folders) (Box 187)
      - 1955-1962, 1972, 1991-1993, undated, (9 folders) (Box 188)
    - South Pole research, 1988-1994 (Box 188)
    - Trans-Antarctic Expedition, Ross Sea Committee, 1956 (Box 188)
    - Treaties, 1958-1961, 1975-1992, (4 folders); (1 folders) (Box 188, Box 189)
    - Tourism, 1990-1994 See also Digital Files, same title (Box 189)
    - Ungulates, 1982-1993 (Box 189)
    - U. S. Antarctic Research Program, 1976-1981 (Box 189)
    - Weddell Sea Bottom Water and Weddell Gyre, 1975-1977 (Box 189)
  - Anthropic principle, 1981, 1989, undated (Box 189)
  - Arctic (Box 189)
    - Greenland, 1976-1981, 1989-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 189)
    - Maps, 1947, 1956, 1967, 1980 (Box 189)
    - Miscellany, 1955, 1967-1990, undated (Box 189)
    - Permafrost, Soviet Union project, undated (Box 189)
  - Asteroids, 1972, 1985-1990 (Box 190)
  - Black holes, 1974-1994 (Box 190)
  - Bogotá, Colombia, 1966, 1988 (Box 190)
  - Bridges, 1929, 1991-1995 (Box 190)
  - Byrd, Richard E., 1958-1963, 1971-1988, (3 folders) (Box 190)
  - Cayman Islands survey, 1976, undated (Box 190)
  - China (Box 190)
    - Birth control, 1978-1978, undated (Box 190)
    - Flood control, canals, irrigation, 1972-1980 (Box 190)
  - Circumstellar disks, 1992 (Box 190)
  - Climate, 1988 (Box 190)
  - Cold fusion, 1985-1989 (Box 190)
  - Comets, 1970, 1986-1990, undated (Box 190)
  - Congressional Office of Technology Assessment, 1976-1978 (Box 190)
  - Continental drift, 1991, undated See also Container OV 4, same title (Box 191)
  - Cooperation, 1982-1992 (Box 191)
  - Core-mantle boundary, 1993-1994 (Box 191)
  - Cosmic dust (brownless particles), 1978, 1986-1989, undated (Box 191)
  - Cosmic rays, 1986-1990, undated (Box 191)
  - Cosmology (Box 191)
    - General, 1956, 1983-1989 (Box 191)
    - Inflationary universe, 1982-1987 (Box 191)
    - Missing mass, 1983-1988 (Box 191)
  - Curtis, Michael, 1957 (Box 191)
  - Cybernetics, undated (Box 191)
  - Dolphins and porpoises, 1966-1967, 1978-1980 (Box 191)
  - Earth, relief, 1969, 1985 (Box 191)
  - Earthquakes (Box 191)
    - Middle East, 1969, 1981-1989 (Box 191)
    - Miscellany, 1964-1995 (Box 191)
    - New York, 1980-1990 (Box 191)
  - Eclipses, 1941, 1969-1970, 1980-1989, undated (Box 191)
  - Electromagnetism, undated (Box 191)
  - Elements, table of, 1956, 1963-1969, 1988-1989, undated (Box 191)
  - Encounter '86: An International Rendezvous with Halley's Comet, 1986 (Box 191)
  - Entropy, 1988, undated (Box 191)
  - Ether, space, undated (Box 191)
  - Fourier transform, 1974, 1989 (Box 191)
  - Fractals, 1986-1987 (Box 191)
  - France, 1970-1977, 1984-1987, undated (Box 191)
  - Flood basalts, 1995 (Box 191)
  - Fusion, 1974-1976, 1981-1993 (Box 191)
  - Galaxies (Box 192)
    - Core, 1980-1990 (Box 192)
    - Jets, 1979-1992 (Box 192)
    - Miscellany, 1980-1988 (Box 192)
  - Gamma bursters, 1992-1994 (Box 192)
  - Gamma ray astronomy, 1985-1993 (Box 192)
  - Gamma rays, 1981-1992 (Box 192)
  - Gamma rays and air showers, 1989-1995, (3 folders) (Box 192)
  - Geology, 1955, 1975-1980 (Box 193)
  - Germany, 1985-1990, undated (Box 193)
  - Gigantopithecus, 1970-1978, undated (Box 193)
  - Gravity, 1987-1989 (Box 193)
  - Guzman, Julian, 1981-1982 (Box 193)
  - Hawaii (Box 193)
    - Big island, 1977-1978, 1987-1988 (Box 193)
    - Mauna Loa and Mauna Kea, 1978-1987 (Box 193)
    - Miscellany, 1983, 1995, undated (Box 193)
    - Oahu, 1981-1987, 1995, undated (Box 193)
    - Settlement; the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI), 1985-1991, undated (Box 193)
    - Ships and navigation, 1977-1986 (Box 193)
  - Iceland photographs, undated (Box 193)
  - Ifugao, Philippines, 1979, undated (Box 193)
  - Impacts, 1995, undated (Box 193)
  - International Astronautical Congress, 1970 (Box 193)
  - International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), memory chips, 1975 (Box 194)
  - International Oceanographic Congress, 1955-1959 (Box 194)
  - Italy, 1961, 1970-1986, undated (Box 194)
  - Japan, 1987 (Box 194)
  - Jupiter (planet), 1965-1979 (Box 194)
  - Jupiter-mass companion, 1995 (Box 194)
  - Lasers, 1965-1966, 1988 (Box 194)
  - League of Naval Destroyermen, 1972 (Box 194)
  - Levanevsky, Sigmund, plane crash, 1983-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 194)
  - Lightning, 1954, 1961-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 194)
  - Mantle plumes, 1989-1993 (Box 194)
  - Mariner Mars 4, 6, and 7 results, 1965-1969 (Box 194)
  - Mars (planet) (Box 195)
    - Miscellany, 1965-1978, 1985-1991, undated (Box 195)
    - Photographs, 1976-1978 (Box 195)
    - Viking project, 1972-1976, 1992, undated (Box 195)
  - Marshack, Alexander, 1972 (Box 195)
  - Mathematicians, undated (Box 195)
  - Mathematics, Greek, undated (Box 195)
  - Mediterranean region, 1978-1995 (Box 195)
  - Mercury (planet), 1974-1975, 1984-1986, undated (Box 195)
  - Meteorites, 1977-1992, undated (Box 195)
  - Methane, 1979-1980, 1986-1990 (Box 195)
  - Missing mass, 1988-1990 (Box 195)
  - Moon, origin and history, 1969-1991 (Box 195)
  - Morton, Howard, undated (Box 196)
  - Nature (magazine), 1961-1963 (Box 196)
  - Nazca lines, 1986 (Box 196)
  - Nebulas, 1989 (Box 196)
  - Neptune (planet), 1988 (Box 196)
  - Nerve regeneration, 1970-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 196)
  - Neutron stars, 1974-1980, 1987, undated (Box 196)
  - New Hebrides, 1980, undated (Box 196)
  - New York water tunnels, 1984 (Box 196)
  - New Zealand (Box 196)
    - Army Board publications, 1943-1945 (Box 196)
    - Government publications (Box 196)
      - Agriculture Department, 1946, undated (Box 196)
      - Health care and benefits, 1946 (Box 197)
      - Maori, circa 1946 (Box 197)
      - Miscellany, 1943-1947 (Box 197)
      - Rehabilitation Department, 1945-1946, undated (Box 197)
      - "Shape of Things to Come," circa 1946 (Box 197)
      - Soil Conservation and Rivers Control Council, 1944-1945 (Box 197)
      - Tourism, 1946, undated (Box 197)
      - War related, 1943-1946 (Box 197)
    - Miscellany (Box 197)
      - 1940-1947, undated (Box 197)
      - 1942-1947 (Box 198)
    - Photographs, undated, (3 folders) (Box 198)
  - North Pole debate, Frederick Albert Cook and Robert E. Peary, 1965-1970 (Box 198)
  - Ocean drilling program, 1986-1993, undtaed, (2 folders) (Box 198)
  - Ocean mining, 1975-1987 (Box 199)
  - Oceana, 1969, 1978-1982, undated (Box 199)
  - Oceanography (Box 199)
    - General, 1936, 1941, 1970-1990, undated (Box 199)
    - Tomography, 1985-1990 (Box 199)
  - Oil spills, 1974-1985 (Box 199)
  - Olbers' paradox, 1984-1989 (Box 199)
  - Opiates, 1977 (Box 199)
  - Otters, 1959-1960, 1988, undated (Box 199)
  - Oxygen revolution, 1981-1986 (Box 199)
  - "P" miscellany, 1966-1969, 1977-1981, undated (Box 199)
  - Panama Canal, 1968-1977, undated (Box 199)
  - Paranoia, 1972-1977 (Box 199)
  - Paranormal, 1975-1978, 1984-1987 (Box 199)
  - Parity, 1966, 1981, 1989-1990 (Box 199)
  - Parkinson's disease, 1979-1988 (Box 200)
  - Particles, 1962, 1975, 1985-1991, undated (Box 200)
  - Pests, 1971, 1981-1983 (Box 200)
  - Petroleum, origin of, 1977-1986 (Box 200)
  - Petroleum reserves, 1986-1987, undated (Box 200)
  - Pheromones, 1981 (Box 200)
  - Photographs (Box 200)
    - Captions, undated (Box 200)
    - Miscellaneous prints and slides, 1945, 1957, 1981-1982, undated (Box 200)
  - Photosynthesis, 1975-1989, undated (Box 200)
  - Physics, general, 1982, 1985 (Box 200)
  - Pictures of land, undated (Box 200)
  - Planets (Box 200)
    - General, 1969-1972, 1978-1984, 1994-1995 (Box 200)
    - Missing, 1978-1984, 1991 (Box 200)
    - Outer planets, 1965-1973, 1981-1985 (Box 200)
  - Plate motions, Christopher Scotese, 1987-1989 See also Digital Files, same title, (2 folders) (Box 201)
  - Plutonium, 1972-1979, undated (Box 201)
  - Polar bears, 1976, 1982-1988, undated (Box 201)
  - Pollution, 1963-1981, 1987, undated (Box 201)
  - Polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs), 1981, 1987, undated (Box 201)
  - Population dynamics, 1965, 1972-1987, undated (Box 201)
  - Population growth, 1974-1990 (Box 201)
  - Prions and scrapie, 1979-1995, undated (Box 202)
  - Privacy, 1968-1986 (Box 202)
  - Primate shortages, 1969-1972, 1981, undated (Box 202)
  - Pulsar binaries, 1969-1975 (Box 202)
  - Pulsars, 1968-1975, 1982-1988 (Box 202)
  - Quantum theory, 1986-1994, undated (Box 202)
  - Rabies, 1975-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 202)
  - Race, 1969-1978 (Box 202)
  - Radar astronomy, 1965-1967 (Box 202)
  - Radiation (Box 202)
    - Beir reports, 1979-1982 (Box 202)
    - Electromagnetic, 1968-1987, undated (Box 202)
    - Low-level effects, 1978-1990, undated (Box 202)
    - Radon, 1978-1987 (Box 202)
  - Radiation hazards, 1969-1981, 1987, undated (Box 203)
  - Radio astronomy (Box 203)
    - Long baseline interferometry, 1975-1988, undated (Box 203)
    - Observatories, 1963-1964, 1970-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 203)
    - Very long array, 1974-1978, 1985, undated (Box 203)
  - Radio galaxies, 1966, 1975-1981 (Box 203)
  - Radioactive waste (Box 203)
    - Disposal, general, 1975-1989 (Box 203)
    - Geologic disposal, 1983-1987 (Box 203)
    - Low level, 1982-1986 (Box 203)
    - Oceanic disposal, 1977-1987 (Box 204)
    - Vitrification, 1981-1988 (Box 204)
  - Rainforest, 1987 (Box 204)
  - Raw materials, 1973-1987, undated (Box 204)
  - Rebirth of a Planet and Hollow Earth Mysteries by Ruth A. Leedy (Floria Benton), 1981-1983 (Box 204)
  - Red shift controversy, 1995 (Box 204)
  - Red shift debate, 1956, 1964-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 204)
  - Red tides, 1975-1986, undated (Box 204)
  - Remote sensing, 1979-1985 (Box 204)
  - Rescue, satellite, 1984 (Box 204)
  - Ribosomes, undated (Box 204)
  - Rip currents, 1973-1975 (Box 204)
  - Risk assessment, 1976-1979, undated (Box 204)
  - River diversion, 1979-1980 (Box 204)
  - Rivers, 1975, 1981-1982, undated (Box 204)
  - Robots, 1979-1988, undated (Box 205)
  - "S" miscellany, 1968, 1978-1989 (Box 205)
  - Sailing ships, 1979-1987 (Box 205)
  - Salmon, 1976-1985, undated (Box 205)
  - Saturn (planet) (Box 205)
    - Miscellany, 1980-1982 (Box 205)
    - Phoebe (moon), 1967, undated (Box 205)
  - Saxe, Robert L., 1973-1977 (Box 205)
  - Schistosomiasis, 1972-1987 (Box 205)
  - Schizophrenia, 1977-1988 (Box 205)
  - Science advising, 1968, 1974-1981, 1991 (Box 205)
  - Science court, 1976-1977, 1986, undated (Box 205)
  - Sea level changes, 1977-1991 (Box 205)
  - Sea rise, 1988-1990 (Box 205)
  - Seismic networks, 1988-1990 (Box 206)
  - Seismology (Box 206)
    - General, 1975-1989, undated (Box 206)
    - Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP), 1974-1982 (Box 206)
  - Sewage, 1976-1981, undated (Box 206)
  - Sex determination, 1981-1987 (Box 206)
  - Sharks, 1960, 1973-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 206)
  - "Shroud of Turin" (Holy Shroud), 1978-1988 (Box 206)
  - Sirius (star system), 1977, 1985-1987 (Box 206)
  - Smog, 1969-1974 (Box 206)
  - Sociobiology, 1976-1978 (Box 206)
  - Soil conservation, 1972-1979 See also Container OV 4, Soil conservation, map in six sections (Box 206)
  - Solar wind, 1970-1985, undated (Box 206)
  - Sonar, 1980-1986 (Box 206)
  - "Soviet Exhibition," New York Coliseum, New York, N.Y., 1959 (Box 207)
  - Space colonies, 1975, undated (Box 207)
  - Spiders, 1976-1983 (Box 207)
  - Stellar evolution, 1970 (Box 207)
  - Submarine communication, 1976-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 207)
  - Submersibles, 1985-1989, undated (Box 207)
  - Sun, 1974-1989, (2 folders) (Box 207)
  - Sun cycles, 1976, 1985-1989 (Box 207)
  - Supernova 1987-A, 1986-1989 (Box 207)
  - Supernova watch, 1975, 1986, undated (Box 207)
  - Supernovas, 1971, 1978-1988, undated (Box 207)
  - Switzerland (Box 208)
    - European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), 1983-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 208)
    - General, 1968, 1977-1987, undated (Box 208)
  - Synfuels, 1981-1984, undated (Box 208)
  - Szent-Gyorgyi, Albert, 1975-1976 (Box 208)
  - Tall buildings, 1976-1980, 1987-1991 (Box 208)
  - Tectonics (Box 208)
    - Alaska, 1979-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 208)
    - Antarctica, 1981-1987 (Box 208)
    - Asia, 1990, undated (Box 208)
    - Atlantic and northeast U. S., 1978-1980 (Box 208)
    - Caribbean and Central America, 1971, 1980 (Box 208)
    - Dissent, 1981-1986 (Box 208)
    - Gulf of Mexico, 1978-1985 (Box 209)
    - Indian Ocean, 1975-1988, undated (Box 209)
    - Maps, 1965, 1972, 1985, 1989 See also Container OV 4, same title (Box 209)
    - Mid-ocean ridges, 1988-1989 (Box 209)
    - Miscellany, 1975-1988 (Box 209)
    - Pacific Ocean, 1978, 1986, 1992 (Box 209)
    - Plume debate, 1973, 1982-1990, undated (Box 209)
    - Red Sea, 1978-1988 (Box 209)
    - Subduction, 1988-1995, undated (Box 209)
  - Tektites, 1970-1989 (Box 209)
  - Telescopes (Box 209)
    - Image intensifiers, 1975-1990, undated (Box 209)
    - Kitt Peak, 1960, 1974, 1987, undated (Box 209)
    - Miscellany, 1959, 1977-1992 (Box 209)
    - Multiple mirror, 1979-1980, undated (Box 210)
    - New generation, 1977-1989, undated (Box 210)
    - Observatories, 1967, 1974-1976, 1982-1993, undated (Box 210)
    - Space, 1982-1989 (Box 210)
  - "Test tube babies," 1984-1987 (Box 210)
  - Tides, 1968, 1978, 1986 (Box 210)
  - Tornadoes, 1965-1987 (Box 210)
  - Trains, 1981-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 210)
  - Tree rings, 1974, 1984-1988, undated (Box 210)
  - Triple junctions, 1970, undated (Box 211)
  - Tsunami waves, 1961, 1974-1978, 1987, undated (Box 211)
  - Tunnelling, 1971-1973, 1979-1988, undated (Box 211)
  - Turbidity currents, 1977 (Box 211)
  - Turtles, 1962-1964, 1979-1990, undated (Box 211)
  - Twins, 1978, 1987-1990, undated (Box 211)
  - Ubiquitin, 1987 (Box 211)
  - Unidentified flying objects (UFOs) (Box 211)
    - Airline pilots, 1967, undated (Box 211)
    - Articles and press releases, 1965-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 211)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1976, 1986 (Box 211)
    - Miscellany, 1966-1980, 1991-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 212)
    - Periodicals and books, 1965-1980, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 212)
    - Photographs, 1966, undated (Box 212)
    - Project Blue Book, 1966-1968 (Box 212)
    - Project Blue Book and Project Grudge, 1968-1970, undated (Box 212)
    - Reports, 1962-1968, undated (Box 212)
  - Uranus (planet), 1975, 1985-1988 (Box 212)
  - Velikovsky, Immanuel, 1966-1991 (Box 213)
  - Venus (planet) (Box 213)
    - Atmosphere, 1970-1971, 1978-1987 (Box 213)
    - General, 1962-1991, undated (Box 213)
    - Surface observations, 1974-1988 (Box 213)
  - Violin varnish, 1983-1984, undated (Box 213)
  - Virgin Islands, 1990-1993 (Box 213)
  - Viruses, 1969-1987 (Box 213)
  - Vitamins, 1973-1978, undated (Box 213)
  - Volcanic hazard maps, 1977-1986 (Box 213)
  - Volcanoes (Box 213)
    - Africa and Italy, 1971-1972, 1979-1981, 1987 (Box 213)
    - Alaska and Aleutian Islands, 1975-1981, 1987, 1993 (Box 213)
    - Cascades, 1980, undated (Box 213)
    - Central America, South America, Carribean, 1971-1980, 1987, undated (Box 213)
    - Climate, 1988 (Box 213)